You now have gained some intuition for how the Central Limit Theorem works.
الآن قد اكتسبتم صورة تخمينية بشكل ما حول كيفية عمل "مبرهنة النهاية المركزية"،
But it doesn't work for all sampling distributions.
لكنها لا تعمل مع جميع توزيعات العينات.
Sure, a mean and proportion are normally distributed with large enough sample sizes.
بالتأكيد يتم توزيع عدد متوسط ونسبة عادةً باستخدام أحجام كبيرة بما يكفي للعينة؛
But what does it mean for a sample size to be large enough?
لكن ماذا يعني أن يكون حجم العينة كبيرًا بما يكفي؟
Is a sample size of 10 large enough?
هل يكون حجم العينة كافيًا إذا كان 10؟
Or 30? Or 100?
أم 30؟ أم 100؟
You might memorize a list of statistics for which the Central Limit Theorem applies.
ربما تحفظون قائمة بالإحصائيات التي تنطبق عليها مبرهنة النهاية المركزية.
It applies for the mean, and for proportions,
إنها تنطبق على العدد المتوسط، وعلى النسب،
and applies for the difference in means,
وتنطبق أيضًا على الاختلافات في الأعداد المتوسطة
and difference in proportions.
والاختلافات في النسب.
However, the Central Limit Theorem doesn't
رغم ذلك، لا تنطبق مبرهنة النهاية المركزية
apply to the sampling distribution for the variance,
على توزيع العينات للمتفاوت
or for the correlation coefficient.
أو لمعامل الارتباط.
It doesn't apply for the sampling distribution of the maximum value in a data set.
لا تنطبق المبرهنة على توزيع العينات للقيمة القصوى في مجموعة البيانات.
With all the data being collected in the world,
رغم وجود كل البيانات التي يتم جمعها في العالم،
and tons of compute power available at our fingertips,
والقدر الهائل من قوة الإحصاء المتاحة في متناول أيدينا،
the Central Limit Theorem is still useful for some sampling distributions.
تظل مبرهنة النهاية المركزية مفيدة لبعض توزيعات العينات.
But instead of relying on this theorem,
لكن، بدلًا من الاعتماد على هذه المبرهنة،
what if we just simulated whatever sampling distribution we were interested in instead?
ماذا لو حاكينا توزيع العينات الذي كنا مهتمين به أيًا كان؟